# KEIVER HERNANDEZ FERNANDEZ

## Senior Web Developer

+1 786 478 1546 | www.keiverh.com | me@keiverh.com

#### **CAREER OVERVIEW**

Passionate web developer with 7 years of experience designing and programming web applications, with a strong background in Agile Development with SCRUM.

Specialized in frontend development with solid knowledge of JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS, jQuery and User Experience Design as well as comprehensive experience in back-end development mainly using PHP; with know-how of open source tools to develop on GNU/Linux environments.

#### **TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES**

Languages: JavaScript, SASS, HTML5, CSS3, XML, JSON, PHP, VB.Net, ASP.NET

Database Management: MySQL/MariaDB, MongoDb, MSSQL Server, Sphinx Server

Tools/Frameworks: AngularJS, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, Grunt, NPM, Bower, Yii2, Codelgniter, Ionic,

Cordova, Composer, Git

**Operating Systems:** OS X, RedHat, Ubuntu GNU/Linux, Windows Server

Areas of Expertise: Web Development, Mobile Development, ERP Customization, Data Analysis, GUI

Design, Web Responsive Design, SEO, TDD, User Experience, Software

Accessibility, SaaS

#### **EDUCATION**

Postgraduate Studies on Teaching and Innovation — University of Computer Sciences, Havana, Cuba (2010 - 2013)

Bachelor of Computer Sciences — University of Computer Sciences, Havana, Cuba (2004 - 2009)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Scrum Master Accredited Certification - Certificate Id: 44385580153670, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2015
Scrum Certification for Web Developer - Certificate Id: 32363845809362, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2016
Scrum Certification for Mobile App Developer - Certificate Id: 37966506729833, http://www.scrum-institute.org/, 2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer • August 2015 – July 2016 Creative Works Inc., Ecuador – (Teqspring Inc., Las Vegas, Nevada, USA) www.creativeworks.com.ec

- Increased user experience with the development of an online purchase catalog using the PHP framework Yii2, jQuery and SCSS
- Assembled web views from project wireframes, using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3
- Designed and put into practice several mechanisms and patterns to clean and identify useful data using PHP regular expressions (PCRE), increasing the quality of the information in more than 80%
- Integrated new version of a search module to include Full Text Search using Sphinx Server and MariaDB

## Front-end Developer • November 2014 – July 2015

Numencorp SA, Quito, Ecuador

#### www.numencorp.com

- Increased management potential for customers by developing new customized modules for an ERP system using AngularJS, JavaScript and Twitter Bootstrap
- Improved customer experience by optimizing how the application handled large volumes of JSON data
- Handled critical issues for already-on-production ERP application instances
- Optimized core code for an ERP application developed with PHP
- Automated several areas of development process with tools like SASS, Grunt, Bower and NPM

## Full-stack Developer • July 2013 – October 2014

Northern Exposed Inc., Toronto, Canada

## www.northernexposed.ca

- Enhanced graphic user interfaces and user experience, adapting sites to a responsive design with
   Twitter Bootstrap and jQuery
- Assessed technologies migration for already-in-production web applications developed in VB.Net
- Improved customer support by developing an internal application to manage change requests
- Increased clients' revenue with the development of e-commerce sites complying with SEO techniques
- Decreased server failure times and improved database structure and maintenance

## Desktop Application Developer/Project Leader • September 2009 – June 2013

ALBET SA, Havana, Cuba

#### www.albet.cu

- Led the development team for an application to create and clone ISO images of GNU/Linux OS
- Evaluated architectural changes and integration issues with Nova GNU/Linux
- Simplified graphical user interfaces and their behavior developed with the Qt Framework